Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection (MS Hyde 10): Guide.
Donald Hyde and Mary Hyde Eccles Autograph Collection,
- Potter, R. (Robert), 1721-1804. Autograph letter, signed, Scarning [Norfolk, England] to [James Dodsley?] 1779 Nov. 29., (570); 1s.
  Sends subscription papers for his translation, The Tragedies of Euripides.
- Priestley, Joseph, d. 1863?. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Samuel Parkes, [1820 Feb. 7] Monday., (571); 1s.
  Hopes to accompany Parkes to the London Institution.
- Prince, Daniel, ca. 1711-1796. Autograph letter, signed, Oxon [Oxfordshire, England] to J. (John) Nourse, 1759 Dec. 5., (572); 1s.
  Orders books and comments on Oxford University Press.
- Psalmanazar, George, 1679?-1763. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Mr. Green, [17--] Friday., (573); 1s.
  Seeking sources on the history of Africa.
- Psalmanazar, George, 1679?-1763. 4 autograph letters, signed, London, to Samuel Reynolds (father of Sir Joshua Reynolds), 1704-1707., (574); 4s.
  The first letter, dated 1704 Aug. 3, protests at length against investigators of his Formosan fraud.
- Pye, Henry James, 1745-1813. Autograph letter, signed, Faringdon House [Berkshire, England] to unidentified recipient, 1784 Apr. 18., (575); 1s.
  Requests an account of his recent election to Parliament.
- Quincy, Josiah, 1772-1864. Autograph letter, signed, Quincy (Mass.), to Miss Arnold of New Bedford (Mass.), 1854 June 19., (576); 1s.
  Sends and comments upon his manuscript transcript of Soame Jenyns's An Epitaph on Samuel Johnson LL.D.
- Read, James, b. 1718. Autograph letter, signed, Reading (Pa.), to William Strahan, 1754 Oct. 28., (577); 1s.
  Recounts a conversation with George Whitefield. Anxious to see Samuel Johnson's Dictionary of the English Language.
- Rees, Abraham, 1743-1825. Autograph letter, signed, King's Road, Gray's Inn [London] to Rev. Mr. W. Jameson, Royston, Hertfordshire [England] 1817 Aug. 23., (578); 2s.
  Cannot recommend A. Bromiley for support from the University of Glasgow's Dr. Williams Trust. On verso, Jameson's autograph letter, signed, Royston [Hertfordshire, England] to A. Bromiley, 1817 Sept. 3. With cover.
- Reynolds, Frances, 1729-1807. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Euphemia?] Boswell, [18--?] April 1., (579); 1s.
  Concerning a letter from Mrs. Stuart.
- Reynolds, Frances, 1729-1807. Order to pay: document, signed, London, 1788 Mar. 27., (580); 1s.
  Order upon Thomas Coutts Co., on account of Sir Joshua Reynolds.
- Reynolds, Samuel, 1681-1745. 2 autograph draft letters, [no place] to George Psalmanazar, 1706 Aug., (581); 2s.
  Expressing concerns over the veracity of Psalmanazar's An Historical and Geographical Description of Formosa. On the verso of the 1706 Aug. 9 letter is an autograph draft letter from Reynolds to Mrs. Baber, mother of his pupil.
- Richardson, William, 1743-1814. Autograph letter, signed, Glasgow College [Scotland] to William Strahan, 1782 Oct. 1., (582); 1s.
  Concerning publication of his Anecdotes of the Russian Empire, which he hopes can be printed similarly to Samuel Johnson's Lives of the English Poets.
- Richmond and Lennox, Charles Lennox, Duke of, 1735-1806. Autograph letter, signed, Goodwood [Sussex, England] to unidentified recipient, 1772 June 19., (583); 1s.
  Concerning the financing of a real estate purchase.
- Rivers, Richard Savage, Earl, ca. 1654-1712. Autograph letter, signed, [London, England] to unidentified recipient, 1711 Nov. 30., (583a); 1s.
  Travel news.
- Rivington, Charles, 1754-1831. Autograph letter, signed, London, to John Farrer (1758 or 9-1820), 1803 Sept. 27., (584); 1s.
  Concerning the publication of Farrer's sermons.
- Robertson, James, 1714-1795. Autograph letter, signed, [University of] Edinburgh [Scotland] to David Stewart Erskine, Earl of Buchan, 1780 June 6., (585); 1s.
  Offers advice on securing a tutor of grammar. Torn, with substantial loss of text.
- Robertson, William, 1721-1793. 2 autograph letters, signed, [University of] Edinburgh [Scotland] to Andrew Strahan, 1787-1789., (586); 2s.
  The 1787 July 16 letter concerns revisions to his History of America.
- Robinson, Henry Crabb, 1775-1867. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Miss Denman, of Upper Norton Street, 1833 Nov. 27., (587); 1s.
  Concerning her dispute over an estate.
- Rochford, William Henry Nassau de Zuylestein, Earl of, 1717-1781. Autograph letter, signed, Berkeley Square [London] to unidentified recipient, 1763 May 13., (588); 1s.
  Concerning a military appointment.
- Rockingham, Charles Watson-Wentworth, Marquis of, 1730-1782. Autograph note, Grosvenor Square [London] to William Petty, Marquis of Lansdowne (then Earl of Shelburne), 1782 Mar. 24., (589); 1s.
  Needs assent of George III, King of Great Britain, to form a new cabinet.
- Rogers, Mary Prowse, 1745-1800. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Samuel Johnson, [1784 Feb.], (590); 1s.
  Agrees to assume Johnson's responsibility for his cousin Elizabeth Herne after his death.
  Quoted in part in Bruce Redford, ed., The Letters of Samuel Johnson (Princeton, N.J.: Princeton University Press, 1994) IV, 288.
- Rogers, Samuel, 1763-1855. Autograph letter, signed, 22 St. James's Place [London] to Robert Monsey Rolfe, Baron Cranworth (then Baron Rolfe), [between 1839-1850] Friday., (591); 1s.
  Accepts invitation.
- Rogers, Samuel, 1763-1855. Autograph letter, signed, Castle Howard [North Yorkshire, England] to [Henry Richard Vassall] Baron Holland, 1834 Oct. 28., (592); 1s.
  Discussing the sons of poet George Crabbe.
- Rogers, Samuel, 1763-1855. Autograph letter, signed, St. James's Place [London] to Sir Anthony Panizzi, [not before 1842] Aug. 20., (593); 1s.
  Asks for an account of Panizzi's travels.
- Rogers, Thomas. Autograph letter, signed, 66 College Street, Bath [England] to his niece Miss Elizabeth Wilson of Berkley House, Frome, Somerset, 1809 Mar. 6., (594); 1s.
  Warning of the dangers of Bath, a "vertex of folly and dissipation."
- Romilly, Samuel, Sir, 1757-1818. Autograph letter, signed, Russell Square [London] to Sir John Cox Hippisley, 1809 Nov. 28., (595); 1s.
  Concerning the Catholic question.
- Romilly, Samuel, Sir, 1757-1818. Autograph letter fragment, signed, Lincoln's Inn [London] to unidentified recipient, 1807 Dec. 28., (596); 1s.
  Offers an opinion in Morier Wilkinson's case.
- Romilly, Samuel, Sir, 1757-1818. Cover: autograph document, signed, London, 1813 Dec. 25., (597); 1s.
  Addressed to Edward Wakefield.
- Romilly, Samuel, Sir, 1757-1818. Memorandum: autograph document, signed, Lincoln's Inn [London] 1807 Aug. 18., (598); 1s.
  Memorandum on the timber rights of tenant John Hole. On verso of what appears to be a fragment of a manuscript transcript of Hole's lease.
- Rosslyn, Alexander Wedderburn, Earl of, 1733-1805 (then Baron Loughborough). Autograph letter, signed, Bath (England), to William Eden, Baron Auckland, 1786 Sept. 6., (599); 1s.
  Social news from Tunbridge Wells and Paris.
- Royal Hospital for Seamen at Greenwich. Account: manuscript document, Greenwich (London), 1710 July 6., (600); 1s.
  Account with John Gilham, carpenter. Signed by Christopher Wren,; Sir John Vanbrugh,; John Mapletoft, and others.
- Rudd, Margaret Caroline, b. 1744 or 5. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Thomas Thynne, Marquis of Bath (then Viscount Weymouth), 1776 Jan. 15., (601); 2s.
  Providing her full account of the forgery charges against Daniel Perreau,; Robert Perreau, and herself. With autograph endorsement, signed, by Thomas Percy.
  Transcript of Percy's endorsement in Adam, 209.
- Ruffhead, Owen, 1723-1769. 2 autograph letters, signed, to William Strahan, 1765-1767., (602); 2s.
  The first letter, ca. 1765 May, discusses an uprising by silk weavers, and the political machinations of John Stuart, Earl of Bute. The second letter, 1767 Oct. 8, discusses health and family.
- Russell, Alexander, 1715?-1768. Autograph letter, signed, London, to William Cuming (1714-1788), 1764 June 30., (603); 1s.
  Concerning their respective medical practices.
- Ryland, John, 1717?-1798. Autograph letter draft, signed, [no place] to Samuel Johnson, 1784 July 31., (604); 1s.
  Concerning a gravestone inscription for Johnson's late wife Elizabeth Jervis Porter Johnson.
- Ryland, Richard, b. 1747. 2 autograph letters, signed, to Rev. Greatheed of Chichester, Sussex [England] 1809., (605); 2s.
  The 1809 Jan. 13 letter forwards a letter from Samuel Johnson, and describes his relationship with Johnson. The 1809 Apr. 1 letter discusses the friendship of Samuel Johnson with his father John Ryland and uncle John Hawkesworth, and the damage to Johnson's reputation by biographers Sir John Hawkins,; James Boswell, and Hester Lynch Piozzi; also promises to send Hawkesworth manuscripts to William Hayley.
- Ryland, Richard, b. 1747. Autograph letter, signed, Savage Gardens [London] to William Hayley, 1809 Apr. 7., (606); 1s.
  Sends manuscripts of his uncle John Hawkesworth, as well as his own biography of Hawkesworth, annotated by Samuel Johnson.
- Salusbury, John Salusbury Piozzi, Sir, 1793-1858. Autograph letter, [no place] to Miss Lloyd, of Bodedern, Anglesey [Wales] 1844 Apr. 1., (607); 1s.
  Sends a Samuel Johnson letter and discusses his autograph collection, but declines to send any Hester Lynch Piozzi letters because of their private nature. The Johnson letter, dated 1782 Dec. 20 and addressed to Hester Lynch Piozzi, is in MS Hyde 1, item (93).
- Salusbury, John Salusbury Piozzi, Sir, 1793-1858. Account: document, signed, [no place] 1858 Apr. 21., (608); 1s.
  Accounts relating to drainage agreement between Salusbury and Netlam Giles, signed by both parties.
- Salusbury, John Salusbury Piozzi, Sir, 1793-1858. License: manuscript document, [no place] 1813 Dec. 4., (609); 3s.
  License to bear the arms of Salusbury, signed by Henry Addington, Viscount Sidmouth;; Sir Ralph Bigland; and George III, King of Great Britain. With a related autograph letter, signed, from James Cathrow,; College of Arms, London, to Salusbury's adopted mother Hester Lynch Piozzi, 1813 Nov. 25; and a related bill from the College of Arms listing charges from 1813 Nov. and Dec.
- Sandwich, John Montagu, 4th Earl of, 1718-1792. Autograph letter, signed, Portsmouth (England), to [Sir Hugh Palliser?] 1773 June 22., (610); 1s.
  Hopes the recipient will not resign his naval post.
- Sannazaro, Jacopo, 1458-1530. Autograph letter, signed, Naples (Italy), to Antonio Seripando, 1519 Jan. 29., (611); 1s.
  Signed as "Syncerus." In Latin
- Saumaise, Claude, 1588-1653. Autograph letter, signed, Leiden (Netherlands), to unidentified recipient, 1637 June 8., (612); 2s.
- Saussure, [Albertine Amelie de, 1745-1817?] Autograph letter, Geneva (Switzerland), to Madame Bennet, 1804 Apr. 14., (613); 2s.
  Discusses the castle at Grignan (France). In French. Author was apparently the widow of geologist Horace Bénédict de Saussure. Annotated in a hand identical to a document elsewhere in this collection concerning Grignan, attributed there to Granville Leveson-Gower, Marquess of Stafford.
- Savage, John, d. 1714 or 1715. Will: manuscript transcript document, Luddesdown, Kent (England), 1714 Nov. 23., (614); 2s.
  Transcript of a will proved 1714 [1715] Jan. 13, and transcribed 1737 Dec. 8. Lists bequests to his nephew Richard Savage (apparently not the poet).
- Savage, Richard, d. 1743. Facsimile letter fragment, [no place] to Thomas Birch, [17--], (615); 1s.
  Consisting mostly of an untitled poem on Birch's abilities as an historian. Facsimile, printed in 1836 by John Murray of Albemarle Street [London]
- Scott, J. Autograph letter, signed, Leiden (Netherlands), to his brother Sir William Scott (d. 1725), 1725 Jan. 16., (616); 1s.
- Scott, Walter, Sir, 1771-1832. Autograph letter, signed, Edinburgh (Scotland), to Sir Robert [Peel?] 1825 June 23., (617); 1s.
  Concerning Catholic emancipation.
- Scott, Walter, Sir, 1771-1832. Autograph letter, signed, Abbotsford [Melrose, Scotland] to Andrew Tawse, Esq., of 15 York Place, Edinburgh (Scotland), 1819 July 29., (618); 1s.
  Returning an indenture.
- Scott, Walter, Sir, 1771-1832. Autograph note, Castle Street [Edinburgh, Scotland] to unidentified recipient, 1823 May 23., (619); 1s.
  Thanks for sending a magazine containing a John Dryden portrait.
- Scott, William, Baron Stowell, 1745-1836. Autograph letter, signed, London, to Sir Robert Chambers, 1783 Jan. 10., (620); 4s.
  Recounts the past four years of his life, sends local news, and reports on the health of Samuel Johnson.
- Scott, William, Baron Stowell, 1745-1836. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Thomas Denman, Baron Denman, [18--], (621); 1s.
  Asks for Denman's opinion on a peerage case.
- Scott, William, Baron Stowell, 1745-1836. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to George Hammond, 1797 Oct. 25., (622); 1s.
  Asks for an adjustment of administrative protocol.
- Scott, William, Baron Stowell, 1745-1836. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Charles Watkin Williams Wynn, 1807 Feb. 4., (623); 1s.
  Discusses sentencing for an unspecified case.
- Scott, William, Baron Stowell, 1745-1836. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [1825] Feb. 26, Saturday., (624); 1s.
  Concerning an application by John Fonblanque.
- Scott, William, Baron Stowell, 1745-1836. List of the Literary Club: autograph document, [no place] [not before 1815], (625); 1s.
  Lists the members of the Literary Club with the dates of their election from 1764 to 1815.
- Sharpe, Charles Kirkpatrick, 1781?-1851. Autograph letter, [no place] to Sir Walter Scott, [ca. 1826?], (626); 1s.
  Passes on an anecdote from Archibald Arnott concerning the heart of Napoleon I, Emperor of the French. Possibly sent for use in Scott's The Life of Napoleon Buonaparte.
- Shaw, William, 1749-1831. Autograph letter, signed, Rochester (Kent, England), to unidentified recipient, 1782 July 21., (627); 1s.
  Seeking patronage through Lord Frederick North. Mentions his support from Samuel Johnson.
- Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Autograph letter, signed, Evian, Savoie (France), to William Godwin, 1816 June 23., (628); 2s.
  Concerning a property settlement with Bryant.
  Roger Ingpen, ed., The Complete Works of Percy Bysshe Shelley (New York: Gordian Press, 1965) IX, 164-166.
- Shenstone, William, 1714-1763. Autograph letter, The Leasowes (Halesowen, England), to Fanny [Dawtrie?] 1754 Apr. 22., (629); 1s.
  Concerning the death of his cousin Mary Dolman, and a dispute with her brother. Possibly missing a second sheet.
- Shenstone, William, 1714-1763. 2 autograph letters, signed, [no place] to [John Scott] Hylton, 1759. Jan. 30 and Nov. 8., (630); 2s.
  Invitations.
  The 1759 Jan. 30 letter is mounted with an engraving of Shenstone by John Hall after Thomas Ross, 1780.
- Sheridan, Thomas, 1719-1788. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [17--] Wednesday., (631); 1s.
- Shipley, Jonathan, 1714-1788 (then Bishop of Llandaff). Autograph letter, signed, Twyford [Hampshire, England] to Mr. Burn, of Duke Street, Westminster [London] [1769] June 4., (632); 2s.
  Concerning the appointment of Charles Poyntz as prebendary at Llandaff. With cover.
- Short, Thomas Vowler, 1790-1872 (then Bishop of St. Asaph). Autograph letter, signed, Newtown (Powys, Wales), to Augustus Pemberton Salusbury, 1849 July 4., (633); 1s.
  Concerning plans for ordination.
- Siddons, Sarah, 1755-1831. Autograph letter, signed, Leeds (England), to James Ballantyne, 1807 July 5., (634); 2s.
  Discusses the return of her sister Elizabeth Whitlock from the United States.
- Siddons, Sarah, 1755-1831. Autograph note, 17 Pall Mall [London] to Charles John Gardiner, Viscount Mountjoy, [1811] Nov. 11., (635); 2s.
  Invitation. With cover.
- Siddons, Sarah, 1755-1831. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to unidentified recipient, [1808 Sept.?], (636); 1s.
  Describing the destruction of the Covent Garden Theatre by fire. Portion of one page cut away, with substantial loss of text.
- Smalridge, George, 1663-1719. Autograph letter, signed, Oxford [England] to William Lloyd (1627-1717), [1696?] Mar. 24., (637); 1s.
  Concerning Francis Gastrell and his Some Considerations Concerning the Trinity.
- Smalridge, George, 1663-1719. Autograph letter, signed, Westminster [London] to Henry Watkins, Esq., of Flanders, [1708] Apr. 22., (638); 1s.
  Recommends his former servant Richard Adams.
- Smart, Christopher, 1722-1771. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Robert Dodsley] [1747] [between July 15 and Aug. 6], (639); 1s.
  Orders books.
  Betty Rizzo and Robert Mahony, eds., The Annotated Letters of Christopher Smart (Carbondale, Ill.: Southern Illinois University Press, 1991), 24-26.
- Smith, Horace, 1779-1849. Autograph letter, signed, 12 Cavendish Place [London] to Charlotte Barrett, 1842 Jan. 15., (640); 1s.
  Offers advice on negotiating with Henry Colburn concerning Barrett's edition of Fanny Burney's papers, The Diary and Letters of Madame d'Arblay.
- Smith, Sydney, 1771-1845. Autograph letter, signed, 56 Green Street [London] to unidentified recipient, 1841 May 7., (641); 1s.
  Declines to purchase book at stated price.
- Smith, William, 1730-1819. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to George Colman, [1772 Oct.], (642); 2s.
  On verso, autograph letter, signed, from Colman to Smith, Covent Garden [London] 1772 Oct 30. Both letters relate to a dispute over an agreement. With cover.
  Partial transcript of Colman's letter in Adam, 68.
- Smithsby, Thomas. Receipt: document, signed, [no place] 1648 Dec. 9., (643); 1s.
  Receipt for pay as royal gardener at Hampton Court [London] Also signed by Thomas Belasyse, Viscount Fauconberg.
- Smollett, Tobias George, 1721-1771. Autograph letter, signed, Boulogne-sur-Mer (France), to William Hunter, 1763 Aug. 11., (644); 3s.
  Concerning Francis Seymour Conway, Marquess of Hertford; and the benefits of sea bathing. With typescript transcript.
  Lewis M. Knapp, ed., The Letters of Tobias Smollett (Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1970), 94.
- Smollett, Tobias George, 1721-1771. A complete history of England: autograph manuscript, [no place] [1757?], (645); 1s.
  A single footnote from Smollett's manuscript concerning taxation under Edward III, which was not published in the 1757 edition of the history. With autograph note, signed, by William Upcott, 1838.
- Smollett, Tobias George, 1721-1771. Contract: autograph manuscript, signed, [no place] 1753 May 5., (646); 1s.
  Contract to edit A Compendium of Authentic and Entertaining Voyages. Also signed by publishers Robert Dodsley,; James Rivington, and William Strahan.
- Southampton, Charles Fitzroy, Baron, 1737-1797. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [Joshua?] Sharpe, 1769 Feb. 20., (647); 1s.
- Southey, Robert, 1774-1843. Autograph letter, signed, London, to [Andrew Bell] 1830 Nov. 26., (648); 1s.
  Concerning Bell's claims as an educational innovator.
  Charles Cuthbert Southey, ed., The Life and Correspondence of Robert Southey (London: Longman, 1850) 6, 122-124.
- Southey, Robert, 1774-1843. Autograph letter, signed, Keswick (Cumbria, England), to Ebenezer Elliott, 1809 Dec. 29., (649); 1s.
  Responds to Elliott's criticism of Madoc. Annotated with notes for a response, probably by Elliott.
- Southey, Robert, 1774-1843. Autograph letter, signed, Keswick (Cumbria, England), to Richard Heber, 1807 Nov. 16., (650); 1s.
  Concerning his literary reputation, and his edition of Sir Thomas Malory's Morte d'Arthur.
  Charles Cuthbert Southey, ed., The Life and Correspondence of Robert Southey (London: Longman, 1850) 3, 116-118.
- Southey, Robert, 1774-1843. Autograph letter, signed, Duke Street [London] to Thomas Hill (1760-1840), [18--?] Friday., (651); 1s.
  Returns a book.
- Southey, Robert, 1774-1843. Autograph letter draft, signed, [no place] to [Thomas Norton Longman] [1806?], (652); 1s.
  Describing his plan for a literary magazine. A later note by Southey, signed and dated 1807 Sept., notes that this plan was used by Longman as a blueprint for the magazine The Athenaeum, launched in 1807 Jan.
- Southey, Robert, 1774-1843. Autograph letter, signed, Keswick (Cumbria, England), to John May, 1808 Nov. 11., (653); 1s.
  Concerning his uncle's wedding, and literary matters.
- Southey, Robert, 1774-1843. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to Sir Henry Taylor, [1828] Oct. 1., (654); 1s.
  Concerning the death of his uncle (Rev. Herbert Hill).
- Southey, Robert, 1774-1843. 2 autographs letter, signed, to Charles Watkin Williams Wynn, 1817-1834., (655); 2s.
  The 1817 Feb. 14 letter concerns the publication of his Wat Tyler, and the 1834 Sept. 27 letter concerns his health.
- Southey, Robert, 1774-1843. Autograph letter, signed, Keswick (Cumbria, England), to unidentified recipient, 1810 Oct. 7., (656); 1s.
  Concerning literary matters, including strong praise for the poetry of Walter Savage Landor.
- Spencer, George John Spencer, Earl, 1758-1834. Autograph note, signed, [no place] to [T. C. (Thomas Christopher) Banks?] 1814 Nov. 6., (657); 1s.
  Orders a copy of Banks's An Historical and Critical Enquiry into the Nature of the Kingly Office.
- Spencer, George John Spencer, Earl, 1758-1834. Autograph letter, Dallington [Northamptonshire, England] to George Steevens, 1789 Dec. 23., (658); 1s.
  Concerning Spencer's library.
- St. Helens, Alleyne Fitzherbert, Baron, 1753-1839. Autograph letter, signed, Madrid (Spain), to [George Hammond?] 1791 July 22., (659); 1s.
  Comments on Hammond's return to England and his "misadventures" in Boulogne-sur-Mer (France).
- Stafford, Granville Leveson-Gower, Marquess of, 1721-1803. Description de l'etat du chateau de Grignan: manuscript document, [no place] 1788 Mar. 4., (660); 2s.
  Description of the castle at Grignan (France), home of Marie de Rabutin-Chantal, marquise de Sévigné. Possibly a transcript. In French.
- Stanfield, Clarkson, 1793-1867. Autograph letter, signed, [no place] to [John Murray, 1778-1843?] [1835?] Mar. 4, Wednesday., (661); 1s.
  Sends a copy of Sir Joshua Reynolds's Infant Johnson for Miss Murray. With 1834 watermark.
- Stanhope, Philip Henry Stanhope, Earl, 1805-1875. Autograph letter, signed, Grosvenor Place [London] to [Lovell Reeve?] 1863 May 20., (662); 2s.
  Offering corrections to a biographical sketch, possibly the one published by Reeve in Portraits of Men of Eminence in Literature, Science, and Art.
- Stanhope, Philip Henry Stanhope, Earl, 1805-1875 (then Lord Mahon). Autograph letter, signed, Grosvenor Place [London] to unidentified recipient, 1846 Apr. 8., (663); 1s.
  Concerning the transcription of French manuscripts.
- Steele, Richard, Sir, 1672-1729. Letter, signed, Cockpit [London] to [Ambrose] Philips, 1709 Apr. 26., (664); 2s.
  Apparently concerning his authorship of the Tatler. With typescript transcript.
- Steele, Richard, Sir, 1672-1729. Autograph letter, signed, Landguard Fort (Harwich, England), to unidentified recipient, 1702 May 23., (665); 1s.
  Writing to an unidentified woman, Steele describes his duties at the fort. Address panel torn off.
- Steevens, George, 1736-1800. Autograph letter, signed, Hampstead Heath [London] to [Richard Gough] 1776 Feb. 5., (666); 1s.
  Concerning a dispute involving work done by engraver J. K. (John Keyse) Sherwin.
  John Nichols, Illustrations of the Literary History of the Eighteenth Century (London, 1817) V, 434.
- Steevens, George, 1736-1800. Autograph letter, signed, Hampstead Heath [London] to Michael Lort, 1782 Dec. 18., (667); 2s.
  Concerning Lort's failure to be elected to the Literary Club, despite Samuel Johnson's sponsorship. With cover.
- Steevens, George, 1736-1800. Autograph letter, signed, Hampstead Heath [London] to [Edmond Malone] [1783 May 10?] Saturday., (668); 1s.